LILLIAN PARIS FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(520)-461-5820 LILLIANPARIS21@GMAIL.COM HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/LILLIANPARIS

PROFILE

Full Stack Web Developer with 3+ years of experience debugging, designing and constructing mobile friendly applications. Currently educating 30+ junior developers; making them marketable assets to the Web Development community. Developed more than 12 responsive & crossbrowser compatible websites, using React & Javascript. Enthusiastic about crafting the ideal websites for businesses, startups and companies to create both a positive and energetic experience.

SKILLS

- React
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- HTML/CSS
- Javascript
- Node.js
- MySQL/NoSQL
- JSX
- AJAX
- SASS/SCSS
- Data Visualization
- Firebase
- Handlebars
- jQuery
- Redux
- Materialize

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT INSTRUCTOR

PERSEVERE | MAY 2021 - PRESENT

- Mentoring 30 junior developers, training them in the industries best practices of frontend development, app development, as well as back-end & mobile friendly.
- Created 20+ lectures, teaching junior developers various computer languages, libraries and frameworks.
- Working to reduce recidivsm in the State of Arizona, bringing new talent to the technology industry.

BRAND SPECIALIST

CHAPMAN AUTOMOTIVE GROUP | OCT2019 - MAY 2021

- Worked alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentation and advertising collateral.
- Assessed the work of competitors to best understand what our brand brings to the table in our industry.
- Identified and maximized sales opportunities, and increased customer retention rates.

CUSTOMER SERVICE

BUFFALO WILD WINGS | JAN 2018 - OCT 2019

- Worked alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentation and advertising collateral.
- Assessed the work of competitors to best understand what our brand brings to the table in our industry.
- Identified and maximized sales opportunities, and increased customer retention rates.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT, CERTIFICATE

UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA | 2019 - 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.is & ReactJS

DEVELOPMENTS

RSVPLANNER

FULL STACK HANDEBARS AND JAVASCRIPT APP

This application lets users input a location and view nearby events. The user can also create an account and sign in, with an email and password. Once the user has created an account they can post events of their own.

PASSWORD GENERATOR

FULL STACK JAVASCRIPT APP

This application serves to create a better sense of security for password keeping. This application is to include a responsive page that gives the user criteria for a password as well as generating one for the user.